stock price of ICC lombar is actually
holding out quite well despite the fact
that it was a bit of a Miss in Q3 let's
connect with gopal balachandran who is a
CFO and chief risk officer at ICI lombar
joining in thanks so much for taking
time out to begin with the motor segment
that has seen quite Healthy Growth and
that's largely been aided by strong two
wheeler uh private vehicle and two
wheeler sales what's your outlook will
this
sustain so I think that's a good
question to start off with uh I think as
you rightly mentioned uh I think if you
look at the market environment in the
context of Auto vehicle sales uh across
segments I think we have seen a lot of
uh positive momentum getting played out
uh for example which is what we had put
out even as a part of our analyst call
that we had last evening uh if you look
at it on the private car side for
example I think we have seen almost
close to about 3 million Vehicles
getting sold uh on two wheeler we have
seen for the market almost close to
about 13 million Vehicles getting sold
and on the commercial vehicle side
almost more than 1 million plus uh
Vehicles getting sold so in that sense I
think uh the market momentum seems to be
very very positive in that backdrop is
where when you look at it in the context
of IC Lombard for us even for us I think
the growth momentum has been uh quite
positive and in fact for the month of
December uh we have actually kind of
gained market share the industry grew at
about 88.8% in overall motor our growth
in motor was almost about 10.8% and
therefore when we look at heading into
quarter 4 for I think we are very very
positive uh in terms of the opportunity
that the segment presents and we have
got all the right lers in terms of
distribution service and technology
which should Aid us to kind of sustain
the momentum that one is seeing in the
context of M you mentioned that you've
been losing market share until December
2023 does you do you have any you have
indicated early signs of that easing out
will you be able to gain market share
going forward how much and how would
pricing actually pan out also for you
going
forward so again I think we'll have to
look put that into context uh so the
thought process of what H Lombard
historically has been to kind of Drive
profitable growth as a theme and
whenever we have seen elevated levels of
competition play out in the market we
have always been taking a bit guarded SL
cautious approach to writing risks which
is why in the last couple of years when
motor as a segment had seen elevated
levels of competitive intensity getting
played out we obviously calibrated
growth and that's the reason why we have
been a bit lower than in so far as
market growth is concerned if you look
at the industry numbers which is
available obviously at a quarter's lagb
uh the first half year numbers reported
numbers for the overall Market seems to
indicate possibly anywhere between 4 to
6% Improvement in the loss ratios of
motor as a category so hence to that
sense there seems to be some some early
signs of easing and it is in that
context is where I kind of talked about
to say that we are very very very
positive in terms of the Outlook that
one is seeing in the context of uh
driving motor in terms of its growth and
while you will seeing the aggregate for
us possibly as I mentioned maybe uh a
lower than market growth but the
relative difference between industry
growth and Isis Lombard has been coming
down uh every quarter and but as I said
for the month of December we have
actually been able to uh grow faster
than the market on the loss ratios I
think it could be a com comination of uh
either pricing getting better or for the
matter of fact I think the relative cost
of acquisition that one incurs in the
context of the expense of management uh
guidelines is something also which
players in the market will have to
calibrate uh so those are two points
that one will kind of watch for as of
now early signs but obviously we will
watch for the trends to play out but the
momentum as I mentioned earlier looks to
be very very
positive okay okay and uh tell us a
little bit more about the health segment
growth was a little slower in retail
Health um is that a conscious effort any
Targets you have in
mind I think so let me put that numbers
in context um I think you're absolutely
right uh when you look at Health as a
category that's been again a preferred
one preferred one whether you look at uh
the corporate health or whether you look
at the retail Health uh uh in in terms
of both the segments uh on the health
side
uh if you see uh on a 9month basis the
industry grew at roughly about 21 22%
our growth has been slightly in excess
of 29% so we have had a significant
outperformance uh in terms of growth and
even in the quarter three for example
the industry grew maybe slightly lower
at about 15% our growth has been in
excess of 24% so we have always had a
significant outperformance in the
overall health portfolio and within that
your point on us growing let's say
relatively faster on corporate Health in
the context of uh retail uh I think
again when you look at in terms of the
market opportunity both of the segments
are preferred segments for us uh we have
definitely seen improvements in pricing
getting played out on the corporate
Health side uh as we speak and therefore
we have been kind of rightfully Capt
capturing the opportunity of growth in
that segment retail health for us is an
area of investment uh we have not been
actively inv ing in the past but over
the last couple of years we have been
significantly making the right
investments in building distribution and
that's the reason why relatively the
growth for us uh has been slightly lower
but uh it is pretty much if you look at
even retail Health as a category uh we
grew slightly in excess of 19% on a
9month basis the industry numbers would
have been slightly lower than 19% so in
that sense we are actually trying to
grow faster than the market but that's
an area where I said uh we're contining
to make investments in expanding
distribution equally significantly kind
of excelling service capability and
creating the night uh right product uh
portfolio so hence one would continue to
see the momentum play out both on
corporate health and Retail Health as
both of them are preferred segments of
opportunities right and how do you see
your net loss ratios uh play out in the
motor as well as the health space and
how comfortable are you on
risk in the cont of uh our own
experiences on motor loss ratios uh
again it is within the range that we are
comfortable with motor as a segment has
got two subs segments motor own damage
and motor third party if you look at
reported numbers for 9 month motor own
damage loss ratios were roughly at about
65% and almost a similar number is what
we had seen on the third party side the
range that we are comfortable with
operating on motor loss ratios on own
damage for example is between 60 to 65%
and on third party we are comfortable
operating at a range of 65 to 70% so the
overall book should operate at anywhere
between 65 to 67 uh so in that sense I
think we are quite comfortable within
the range at which we are operating at
and uh also I think we end up doing a
lot more in the context of uh claims
management uh that's a area of focus
that we significantly focus on and hence
to that extent is where I think we are
comfortable with operating in the range
of 65 to 67% in motor as a category in
so far as the loss experience is
concerned on the health side I think the
loss ratios could vary depending on
whether you are making your offerings to
a corporate or whether you're making
your offerings to a retail customer on
the corporate side I think even in the
past when we have kind of spoken to the
channel uh we have talked about the loss
ratios on the corporate Health side in
the range of 94 95% and if even if you
you would have looked at the 9 month
numbers reported for us the number has
been at about 95% on retail health
uh Indemnity we have talked about us
being comfortable in the range of 65 to
70% and for the 9 months the retail
Health loss ratios has been around 66%
or thereabout so on both the segments I
think given the opportunity that one is
seeing in terms of the positive momentum
on growth but equally given the focus
that we have in terms of the loss
management or claim service capability
that we are creating I think we are
quite comfortable with the loss ratio
ranges that we are operating at now
ratio is at three almost 104 this is
much better than what the street was
penciling in could you reach a number of
102 earlier than what You' guide it
for I think it's again a great question
so I think this has to be again looked
at in the context of the market uh so if
you look at the again uh just to kind of
refresh Market numbers are always at a
quarter's lag the industry combined
ratios uh for the overall industry is at
about
112% uh it is in that context is where
you see IC Lombards combined ratios at
about 13.6%
uh let's say for quarter three uh
obviously if the market improves the
ability of Isis lombar to obviously
exhibit a better outcome is always there
and that's something that we actively
look at and uh work towards directional
change in so far as Improvement in
Combined ratios are concerned even the
reported combin that you see whether it
is for quarter three or whether it is
for nine months this year relative to
what we have seen as catastrophic events
play out in the previous year we have
had pretty much every event or a flood
event in every quarter uh which is why
we also put out separately the impact
that we have seen on account of flood
losses uh so for the for the nine months
we had an impact on floods of almost
close to about 1.37 billion rupees as
compared to let's say just about 28
crores impact that we had seen in the N9
months last year so even if you were to
kind of factor that out uh the combin
issues would have been much better at
even 10 12.3% has against 13.6% for the
quarter but your point on we look at
let's say accelerating the thought
process that we have put out to the
market of getting to a combined of 102%
by the end of
fi25 uh as of now I think we're sticking
to that number but obviously I think we
will come back maybe in a quarter or two
depending on how we see the market
environment play out definitely we will
not let any of the opportunity lose
whether it is in terms of growth in
revenues or for the matter of fact uh
the Improvement in Combined ratios of
profitability that we can exhibit uh for
uh the company as a
whole all right and could you walk us uh
through and tell us some of the details
of the new product launches any
particular segments that you
target home insurance will be clearly a
significant area of opportunity that one
sees in the context of driving growth uh
if you look at uh globally liability
insurances play a very very critical
role and they they kind of contribute to
a very large proportion of the property
and the casualty Market uh in the Indian
market again what we're getting to see
is is a lot more digitization and uh
technology initiatives play out in that
context is where you also possibly get
to see a lot of risks resulting from uh
the digital trans transformation that
we're doing as a country as a whole so
therefore to that extent you may
possibly get to see some of the
liability insurances cyber liability for
example uh could be an emerging product
that could again uh see uh a huge
Prospect in some in terms of the
opportunity that one is ex itting on
health I think we are continuously kind
of working on improving the entire
product stream to make sure that we have
a product that kind of largely caters to
different customer requirements it could
be either in terms of the various uh age
groups it could be in terms of the life
style uh that one leads etc etc and
therefore uh continuously something uh
you may get to see us uh coming back to
the market informing from time to time
in terms of some of the new products
that we want to launch in the context of
the health offering as well on motor I
think uh what we did maybe last year was
we kind of introduced almost about three
offerings uh which was primarily to kind
of say that you can pay based on the
distance or the miles that you are
driving in terms of the premiums that
you pay unlike a standard premium that
you pay for a one-ear risk uh so here
you kind of pay for the distance of uh
travel that you do and correspondingly
you pay motor premium corresponding to
that or you could pay a premium based on
your driving scores or driving
attributes so so that's basically a pay
as you drive uh and finally we also kind
of launched what we call as motor on
floater uh many times you get to see a
customer having more than one uh asset
uh so a motoron floater helps you to
kind of combine both individual
offerings into one single insurance
policy and in the process it's it stands
beneficial for the
customer right um so IFRS IFRS Norms
will be implemented from fi 6 onwards
right do you expect to see an
improvement uh in profitability on
account of
this uh we are in the midst of kind of
doing the financial impact assessment of
what would it entail in so far as
transitioning to IFR is concerned but
broadly what I can talk about is there
are two three key changes that one is
likely to see when you move to IFRS uh
one is uh in the context of the
acquisition cost that you incur under
the current Indian Gap guidelin
all cost that you incur for sourcing of
a premium or a sourcing of a risk they
get expensed out immediately whereas in
the context of inds or IFRS your
acquisition cost will be allowed to be
amortised over the contract period so
hence in that sense that's a positive in
the context of uh if you were to look at
it visa the current Indian Gap
guidelines the second element is some of
the on the claims side there are certain
lines of businesses where the
development of claims or development of
losses happen over a very long period of
time so for example motor third party
now there again while you're required to
pay for a claim over a longer period but
under the Indian Gap guidelines you are
required to provide for reserves on a
nominal basis uh you are not allowed to
do any discounting of reserves uh as you
transition to IFRS or inds form of
reporting uh you may be allowed to
Discount uh those uh reserves as well
particularly for the segments which have
a very very long tail of claim
development so that's again positive if
you look at in the context of uh
relative to the Indian Gap guidelines
and the third is uh in the context of
Investments where currently the Indian
Gap guidelines do not require us to do a
mark to Market uh in so far as the pnl
is concerned whether it is for the
equity portfolio or whether it is for
the debt uh debt portfolio that we have
so hence in that sense there is no Mark
to Market impact uh any profit or loss
gets reflected only on actual
realization of sale of those securities
uh in so far as IND or IFRS is concerned
we will be subject to Mark to Market uh
on the Investment Portfolio hence to
that extent we may have to come back to
the market every quarter and explain the
performance impact if any consequent to
the mark to Market that goes through the
panal
earnings all right thanks so much uh for
taking time out good to have you on
board that's the word coming in from the
management of ICI Lombard positive
momentum across the board price
Improvement as well is playing out and
they have started investments in retail
health